Guide to the Charles Gordon Post Papers, approximately 1975-1997
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Charles Gordon Post Papers
approximately 1975-1997
Post, C. Gordon (Charles Gordon), 1903-
6.0 cubic feet (17 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Post's diaries as well as correspondence to Post after his tenure at Vassar College.
Biographical Note
Charles Gordon Post, Vassar College professor emeritus of Political Science 1933-1969, received his Ph.D. from The Johns Hopkins University in 1933. In 1930, Post studied at the London School of Economics and Political Science for six months.
Post is the author of The Supreme Court and Political Questions, published in 1936; Significant Cases in British Constitutional Law, published 1957; and An Introduction to the Law, published October 1963. He co-authored two pamphlets with VC President Henry Noble MacCracken entitled Invitation to Freedom and Fair Play. Post collaborated on various other projects, as well.
Dr. Post served on the Committee on Undergraduate Education of the American Political Science Association. During the war, Post served as a member of the Town of Poughkeepsie War Finance Committee. Finally, Dr. Post was active in the Vassar College theatre community, taking part in more than twenty productions of Vassar's Experimental Theatre.
After retiring from Vassar in June 1969, Post was appointed as the Robert D. Campbell Visiting Prodessor at Wells College, Aurora, New York. Post continued there until 1985. Post died 18 February 1997 in Poughkeepsie, NY.
Chronology
11 Nov 1901 Charles Gordon Post born, Puerto Rico
1925 Graduated The Johns Hopkins University
1933 Received Ph.D., The Johns Hopkins University
1933-1969 Vassar College Political Science Professor
1969-1985 Wells College Visiting Professor
18 Feb 1997 Died, Poughkeepsie, NY
Scope and Content Note
The Charles Gordon Post Papers contain Post's diaries as well as correspondence to Post after his retirement from Vassar College.
Access
This collection is closed for research until 18 Feb 2027 according to the agreement between Charles Gordon Post and the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Faculty
Subjects:
Political science--Study and teaching--United States; Political scientists--United States--Biography
Document Types:
Diaries
VCL Categories
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 19 Mar 2009.
Container List
- Correspondence
  - (Box 1)
  - (Box 14)
- Diaries
  - undated, (1 diary, 1 scrapbook) (Box 2)
  - undated, (2 diaries) (Box 3)
  - undated (Box 4)
  - 3 Aug 1976 - 24 Sep 1977 (Box 4)
  - 1977] - 22 Feb 1980 (Box 5)
  - Feb 1980 - Feb 1981 (Box 5)
  - 23 Feb 1981 - 11 Nov 1981 (Box 6)
  - 12 Nov 1981 - 1 Jan 1983 (Box 6)
  - 3 Jan 1983 - 27 Jan 1984 (Box 7)
  - Nov 1984 - Sept 1985 (Box 7)
  - 10 Sept 1985 - 13 May 1986 (Box 8)
  - 18 May 1986 - 10 Jan 1987 (Box 8)
  - 14 Jan 1987 - 22 Sept 1987 (Box 9)
  - 24 Sept 1987 - 7 June 1988 (Box 9)
  - 17 June 1988 - 17 Feb 1989 (Box 10)
  - [1989?] (Box 10)
  - 16 Dec 1989 - 11 July 1990 (Box 11)
  - 14 July 1990 - 14 Mar 1991 (Box 11)
  - 15 Mar 1991 - 19 June 1991 (Box 12)
  - 21 June 1991 - 1 Feb 1992 (Box 12)
  - 2 Feb 1992 - 17 Nov 1992 (Box 13)
  - 2 May 1996 - 20 Sep 1996 (Box 13)
  - undated, (2 diaries) (Box 15)
  - undated (Box 16)
  - "Vol. V,", undated (Box 16)
  - 20 Nov 1992 - 1 Nov 1993 (Box 16)
  - 3 Nov 1993 - 3 Apr 1994 (Box 17)
  - 9 Apr 1994 - 17 Feb 1995 (Box 17)
  - 29 Feb 1995 - 30 Dec 1995 (Box 17)
  - 9 Jan 1996 - 1 May 1996 (Box 17)
  - 22 Sep 1996 - 12 Feb 1997 (Box 17)